hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast this podcast is
designed for coaches speakers mentors
and trainers who want to make as much
money as possible by attracting their
ideal client and closing more sales
using the internet if that's you you're
in the right place be sure to subscribe
to the podcast we got over 200 episodes
for people just like you as well as the
YouTube channel has over a thousand
YouTube videos to help you grow your
business
I'm excited today we're going to talk
about attracting your ideal client
for your coaching for your mentorship
and how to make sure that you get the
right people to join you on that there's
a problem that ends up happening that I
notice with a lot of coaches mentors and
speakers in the beginning is they have a
desire to help a lot of people a wide
range of people
and
that desire actually ends up hurting
their
other desire of growing a business
because
it's counterintuitive
they think that okay The Wider I go The
Wider net I cast I'm going to impact
more people
all the time that turns into less impact
it's it's very interesting
but it's because
when we use the internet to Market we're
using algorithms and artificial
intelligence and the artificial
intelligence shows stuff based on what
people are interested in so if you cast
a wide net
uh you're pretty much guaranteeing that
you're going to get the wrong people
that jump into that net instead you want
to get really specific as to two things
who can you actually deliver results to
and who's going to actually buy what
you're selling okay
this is such a controversial topic with
a lot of coaches and speakers because
they adamantly are like but my message
can help so many people
this is where you might need to let go
of that
attachment to needing to help a wide
range of people
and realize what's actually going to be
effective and by the way
see here's what ends up happening with
coaches
they cast a wide net
I'm gonna help tons of people and they
maybe get
one percent of the market that they
could reach
when they Niche down
they're going to get the same one
percent of people but they're going to
end up getting
10 to 20 percent
of those people because the algorithm is
trained that way so this is what's
interesting let's say that there are
10 000 people that you could potentially
get this year
into your business okay
and you might be saying wow like only a
hundred people would be amazing let's
just let's just go with a hundred okay
let's say you get 100 let's say that
this year you get a hundred people into
your mentoring or you're coaching it's
the hundred people
okay
then that's best case scenario
honestly most of the clients that we
work with do way better than that I get
thousands but for the sake of the
example whatever you can visualize
and let's say that that hundred is ten
percent of that market
well by casting a wide net you're not
gonna get 200.
you're probably only end up going to
attract five to ten people out of this
hundred that you could get by actually
niching down specifically and so it's
counterintuitive oh I'm gonna cast a
wide net I'm going to get all these
people
and every single time it turns into way
less people actually come in because of
the way that the algorithms work because
of the way that using the internet works
today in 2023 we have to get very
specific as to who we can deliver
results to
and who is going to buy from us I can
get a ton of people on my email list but
if they're the wrong people that are not
a good fit for what I actually help
people with specifically
and and and
case in point this right here that I'm
talking about a lot of coaches and
speakers do not like
because they see it as alienating a
whole segment of the market neglecting
wonderful people that they could be
helping
I'm sorry but doing this is actually
gonna be spinning your wheels and you're
gonna struggle to actually reach the
potential of what you're trying to reach
see
oh my goodness
this is the paradigm shift and it's a
mental paradigm shift a lot of people
see they're like wide net bigger numbers
no it's actually lower numbers when you
cast a wide net the amount of people
that you're actually going to impact is
going to be greater when you Niche down
and when you don't focus on such a wider
group of people because the algorithms
are going to find more people that are
actually going to engage with you for
what you spend and you're not going to
lose money in your ad spend
and so
break up with the whole sort of ethical
like you might be seeing this and saying
that's not ethical to only target a
small group of people when I know my
message could help all these people
I know that it could help all these
people I hear this so often from
make impact the goal not money
well would you rather impact
only one percent or ten to twenty
percent by actually niching down
and and and so what it is is you
actually end up going deeper when you
get specific and attract the right group
of people
the volume actually goes up the number
of people that you actually reach
increases
this is the big lie that people believe
about online marketing is that wide net
is going to bring in more people it'll
bring in more of the wrong people who
will end up unsubscribing being
ungrateful not liking what you're
talking about
confused and ultimately never getting
impacted all because
somebody's ego needed to cast a wide net
or they felt called the cast away and I
I have a calling to reach this group of
people
great but you're not going to reach them
with that message
until you Niche down specifically to the
right person who you can impact by
attracting the ones that fit into the
niche that gets results
and becomes a buyer with you okay now
the people that I'm talking to
they want to make a quarter million to
half a million dollars a year
so I'm not gonna be talking to anybody
else who doesn't fit into that category
because just quite frankly none of what
I talk about is even relevant and you're
not going to be able to do anything that
I talk about because you won't have
enough cash flow
okay we use paid advertising to be able
to do this which is why having buyers is
so important
how are you going to fund the paid
advertising without buyers
you're not okay and so that's a big part
of that is we have to get really clear
on what do you do specifically what is
the value that you bring to the table
specifically that you help coaches with
and this happens by getting as specific
as possible
with the result that you deliver to
people and by being able to articulate
it as specific as possible okay
for instance
I don't sell I don't work with coaches
and speakers that want to do offline
seminars or things offline and I don't
work with people that don't want to use
social media and I don't work with
people that don't want to make a ton of
money now obviously some of those people
do end up creeping in and if that's you
I'm sorry you're listening to this I'm
sorry that you're you're here
I can't help you I everything that I
teach is just going to be like foreign
to you you can either stay here and and
try to become that or turn off the
episode right now and for some of you
you're like that's weird Jeremiah why
would you do that why would you say that
why would you try to get people to to
leave listening to you because
this actually makes my impact go up
the algorithm shows my content based on
how far people get through the podcast
episodes based on how far they listen to
me based on how far they go with me
and so if I have the wrong people
listening to my podcasts
doesn't help
if I put you know can't you just let
people stay and listen be kind be be
nice be be a nice person
like I'm being rude or something saying
all this this isn't about me trying to
control other people
this is about
what is financially prudent for my
business
and
the number one thing that I prioritize
in my business is making the most amount
of money while impacting the right group
of people and so my goal is to repel
the ones that are not a good fit
in my messaging in the language that I
use I want to make sure that they are
nowhere near
what I talk about
that they're nowhere near
my call to action okay
this allows me to actually impact more
people because it trains the algorithm
specifically to hone in and laser focus
in on the right group of people that we
want to connect with you know I get a
lot of nasty messages from people for
saying this can you stop talking about
repelling people can you stop talking
about you know you don't want a certain
group of people it's not that I don't
want you like I love all people I love
people
but at the end of the day
if
everybody starts listening to my podcast
I'm not going to have the kind of impact
or business
that I'm called to create that I know
works and this for the last 20 years has
been consistent every time I deviate
from this one thing of focusing in on
who can I get results for and who can I
help the most our business loses now you
might say how is any of this relevant to
me
that's a hundred percent relevant to you
and thanks for continuing to listen to
this podcast episode why is it 100
relevant to you because you have to do
the exact same thing in your business if
you even want a chance
to make money in your coaching business
if you even want a a slight chance
of making six figures you're dead in the
water if you don't do this
100 percent
and you're not gonna make the kind of
money or the kind of impact that you
want
until you specialize down as to getting
very specific as to who you help
I I hear a lot of people they're they're
too much of a generalist and there's a
lot of teaching out there from a lot of
coaches about how generalists make more
money and things like that
that's in Corporate America by the way
that those teachings come from
if you want to make the most amount of
money in your coaching and speaking
business you have to get specific as to
who you can most likely help and you do
this by identifying what are the goals
and desires
of the group of people that you want to
specifically work with
and for most coaches and speakers they
have no clue what these are
they have no clue because they have
their message and they're too concerned
about sounding like a professional and
and and people listening to them and
liking them and their brain is not even
connected to how you actually attract a
group of people to you
to actually purchase what you're doing
okay most people that I meet most
coaches most mentors most speakers are
mentally incapable
of doing what I'm talking about right
now because they're way too focused on
everybody approving of them everybody
liking them people pleasing doing
everything quote unquote perfect and the
right way and best practices quote
unquote
and you're not going to make a half a
million dollars plus doing that you're
just not
so you got to hone in on specifically
who you can help
what are their pain points what are
their struggles
and this and this might be a big shift
for you
this might be a painful shift for you
this might not be what you want to hear
I get that
I got a lot of people who want me to
teach something else than this but I'm
not going to because this is what pays
the bills
and so when you make it your mission to
become relentlessly curious
with your target market as to what they
struggle with
and what their goals and desires are you
can create what's called an ideal client
profile okay and this is how we grow
these businesses we end up profiling
A specific group of people and listen if
you have a problem with profiling A
specific group of people
nothing I say from this point on is
going to help you okay
by profiling who specifically you can
get the most results with and you do
this by analyzing direct responses from
people that come in on the internet okay
and then you solve Niche specific pain
points so there might be a whole group
of people out there that you can help
with your message but your goal is to
find the people that you can deliver
results to
and who are going to be buyers
let's say you got a hundred topics you
could speak or coach on
but but the group of people who
you can deliver results and when I say
results I'm talking about case studies
testimonies producing actual tangible
results people want and they will pay
you money for maybe there's only five of
those 100 topics then you need to stop
talking about the 95 topics that do not
fit into this right here
you get what I'm saying
you get what I'm throwing down and then
you build a whole business around
expanding around these five topics that
connect with these buyers and that
deliver results
we did this with with a number of our
clients by paying attention to what does
the customer want
what are they struggling with and by
making it important to figure that out
and allowing the clients that we bring
in to actually lead the conversation of
our coaching of our trainings of our
speaking of our events and our of our
content
okay
client driven
results driven
messaging
buyer driven messaging is what produces
500k plus results in your business as a
speaker or coach trying to have all
these different messages out here
that may impact people may help them
but do not convert to client results and
buyers big fat wasted time and by the
way
once you get the results and you're
making good money
go ahead and talk about more of these
passion project topics go ahead and talk
about more of these topics that don't
directly relate to your bottom line okay
but you gotta focus in on sales and
marketing as the top priority
in your business and focus on what are
the specific topics as a coach and
speaker that solve very specific
problems it's easier to sell a
painkiller
than to sell a dream
I'm going to say that again
it's easier to sell a painkiller than a
dream
and so if you solve a problem for
somebody you alleviate a pain that
simultaneously produces a dream result
for somebody you have a win-win
and so you got to become curious what
are the pain points what are the
struggles what are the goals of the
people that I work with what are the
goals of the people that are most likely
to spend money with me
and then how can I
just consistently talk about how to help
those people get their goals how to get
very specific
profile the ideal client profile of
who
is gonna spend the most money with me
and
is also going to get the dream result
that they want we have clients that make
multiple six seven and even eight
figures by using this framework we have
a lot of people who have come through
our system
in our testing
that didn't resonate with this message
and they're still struggling to get
clients the ones who actually resonate
with us who actually use this
and they focus in on this part of the
framework
it converts like wildfire all of your
offers all of your lead magnets all of
your courses all of your coaching
because you get very specific
about who you're going to help
how you're going to help them and
delivering a result
now the problem that ends up happening
here that I see most often is some
people are like well I don't know how to
help people I don't know what to help
people with that's a whole other
conversation we have a podcast episode
on actually finding your Niche
specifically but when you find a niche
you're always going to get more specific
more specific more specific Niche down
deeper and deeper and deeper as to what
the desired result of your customer is
what is that desired result that they
have so for instance in my business when
I started
when I started in my business and every
six months I end up evaluating my Niche
more and more
we've reevaluated in the last six months
and are really dialing in on the ones
who want to make the most amount of
money I do not work with a coach or a
speaker if they are not wanting to grow
their email list right away
run campaigns run ad campaigns and
increase the cash flow in their business
there's a lot of great coaches a lot of
great mentors a lot of great speakers
out there I'd love to help them they
don't particularly connect with me
there's a lot of great coaches that can
help those people that's not what we
Niche down for and so in the beginning
in my business I started I had a goal of
I want to just help everybody who's on
the internet okay
this is everybody who's on the internet
that has a business and wants to make
money okay
and I said I can show you how to run
paid ads if you're somebody who's on the
internet who wants to make money I'm
going to show you how to build a simple
website and run paid ads that's a lot of
people that's a wide net of people we've
made very we we made very little money
targeting this group of people
and what I noticed was out of this group
of people who was actually spending the
most amount of money with me and who was
getting results
coaches
and speakers
and mentors
and trainers
that's it so over here we got MLM
e-commerce
um
agency business owners like Graphics
designers people who run ads for other
people things like that so I completely
eliminated even trying to Target or
connect with this group of people pissed
off a lot of them they weren't happy
with this and focused my whole business
about a year about a year and a half ago
into this Niche right here
okay
and so then we did some testing did some
testing and did some testing we found
wait a sec okay out of this group
there's a whole split
about 50 of them
fifty percent of trainers mentors
coaches and speakers they do they want
to do everything offline they don't want
to do anything with with social media
they don't want to do anything with the
internet they want it all to be in
person
and then the other group wants to do it
all online and learn social media and so
I figured out okay I need to eliminate
this whole offline group I'm not trying
to convince them that they should use
the internet I'm going to focus on the
group of coaches mentors speakers and
trainers that want to use the internet
to grow their business
okay now what we found
is that there's a whole group of coaches
mentors and speakers that they do not
want to make money
they see money as a bad thing
and so that's where the market is then
split for us is
this is what we call
impact first
impact Focus message driven
just you know don't ask for the sale
very passive kind of codependent
and then we have the group that is like
actual business owners they actually
want to make as much cash flow as
possible
and so what we've niched down in is
coaches trainers mentors and speakers
who want to use the internet to make as
much cash flow as possible
in their business and that's who we help
and that's who we engage with and that's
who joins our programs and that's who
listens to our podcast and that's who we
end up connecting with okay
so but it started by me casting this
wide net of all the people that were on
the internet
and then getting very specific into the
ones
who want to make the most amount of
money as quickly as possible
and that are willing to learn new skills
that are willing to go put themselves
out there
that are willing to take risks
that are willing to try new things and
and listen if that's you
then you're in the right place this
podcast is specifically designed for you
if you listen to my podcast episodes
you're gonna get a ton of results from
what we talk about and I address a lot
of the things that hold coaches back
a lot of the things that hold mentors
back if we take a look at the previous
podcast episodes let's just take a look
at this right right now
the the grow Your Life podcast here we
got the wealthy coach mindset how to get
your mind right about making money
that was last week's episode we got
break free from victim mentality what to
say to close more sales on your Live
Events how to lower your ad costs with
the feedback loop
how to use chat gbt to help you with
emotional healing and Trauma
how to come up with killer content ideas
never run out of ideas launching when
you have self-doubt
how to sell fearlessly without cringe
hyper manipulation these have been our
podcast episodes since February and so
all of those if that resonates with you
you're in you're in good company you're
you're part of my group people that best
connects with us okay
and so for the people that don't
resonate with that I'm not sure why they
would even listen to me maybe they want
to learn something from what we talk
about but what we talk about very
specifically is just how to make the
most amount of money possible
by selling
and getting sales and delivering sales
without hype without cringe without
manipulation to impact people because
trust me we're impacting lives I believe
that coaches trainers and mentors change
lives but we got to bring in cash flow
first for that to happen and how do you
bring in cash flow by getting more
specific more specific more specific as
to who you help your ideal Target client
that you will deliver results to and who
will become a buyer okay and so what
this does is this allows you to create
your marketing campaigns your language
your Facebook ads your targeting to
specifically Target that group of people
most often and that's what delivers
results okay listen if you're if you're
listening to this podcast right now
check out over at my website
jeremycorkowski.com we host Live Events
often you'll find them over there on my
website they're free most of the time
um you can sign up for them you you can
check them out to help you specifically
grow your business in this you know this
month we're doing growing your email
list and how to start your coaching
business from scratch and and and and
how to use paid ads to get clients and
how to launch offers that actually
connect and scale coaching businesses to
six figures and so if that's you if that
resonates with you make sure to check
that out over at our website grow your
life everybody we'll talk soon have a
good one